(hoof beats pounding)
- I was thinking about you yesterday.
Friend of mine in Jackson Hole
was talking about their rodeo.
Bozeman doesn't have one. Why not?
- Well that's 'cause nobody
here cares about rodeos.
- Oh, you're wrong, John.
Every millionaire I know
wants to be a cowboy.
Authenticity's the one
thing that money can't buy.
It'd be good for Bozeman
and a great way to honor men like you.
- Well, parading just in
front of your friends,
Dan, isn't an honor.
It's a, it's an insult.
You wanna build subdivisions.
Move to Dallas, I won't have 'em here.
Yeah, that's right.
Nothing happens in this
valley I don't know about.
- Called progress, John.
And progress doesn't need your permission.
- Yeah, in this valley it does.
- Why do you care what I build?
You expect me to believe
that you're concerned
about the environment?
You raise cattle, you fucking hypocrite.
You know what I think it is?
I think it's ego.
I think it chaps your ass to walk
through a grocery store and
nobody knows who you are.
- You bet your ass it does because
every family you move in
moves a family I know out.
- With every winner, there's a loser.
- First thing you said I agree with.
Can't stop it, John.
- Watch me.
- Go ahead.
Say it.
It'll make a lawsuit much simpler.
Say stop building or else.
(horse whinnying)
- I'm skipping straight to or else
with you, you cocksucker.
And from now on, or
else is all you get it.
And by the way,
you owe me a horse, you son of a bitch.
(hoof beats pounding)
- Connor, two more.
(soft country music)
- Oh, hi, Dan.
Who's this?
- I'm his wife.
- Beth Dutton.
I run mergers and acquisitions
for Schwartz and Meyer.
- You work with Dan?
- Oh, we flirted with a
couple of things, right?
(soft country music)
That's quite the shiner you got there.
- He was in a car wreck.
- Those airbags, they sure pack a punch.
So, you guys out for a
little afternoon cocktail?
- It's the only kind.
The whole city shuts down at nine.
- Plenty of trouble if
you know where to look.
You should give me a call sometime.
I'll help you find it.
- (laughs) I could use some trouble.
- Well, I'm your girl.
- (laughs) Oh my God, I think
I finally met a friend here.
(chuckling)
You're not leaving, are you?
- Not on your life.
- I'll be right back.
- Okay.
(laughing)
(soft country music)
Remember what I said, Dan. Generations.
- Think I wanna fuck you?
- Oh.
A deal's a deal.
Besides, I'm not fucking you.
I'm fucking her.
And if you have a brother,
I'm fucking him too.
I am chopping your family tree down.
Thank you.
Send her over when she
gets back, would you?
(soft country music)
- I only see one legitimate
bank on this proposal sheet.
- Goldman Sachs and
Chase won't go near him.
He had a bankruptcy in '09.
- What a fucking hack.
Akron Capital.
- VC firm out of Encino.
- Oh, that's how he does it?
Dumb money in California,
of which there is an endless supply.
- Evidently not.
Look at his credit. It's the next file.
- He has two mortgages on his house?
Jason, this guy has leveraged everything.
Every penny is tied up
in this development.
Moving that river really fucked him.
- Look at File Three.
- He's trading on the OTTC.
Aw, I am not that lucky.
It's at three bucks a share.
I'm gonna be on his board by Monday.
- What are you doing here?
(soft rock music)
- I'm not gonna smoke in
your living room, Dan.
I do have boundaries.
- Where's my wife?
(upbeat rock music)
♪ I been stumbling down the mountain ♪
(laughing)
- Woo!
- You are hot.
♪ Baby I lost my way ♪
- I took you for a cuckold.
Guess I was wrong.
You brought this on yourself, Dan.
- I'm gonna ruin you.
I'm gonna ruin you and your
entire fucked-up family.
- You hurt my father, I hurt you back.
This isn't hurting you, Dan.
This is just
fun.
No, hurting you is gonna
be tomorrow morning,
when I purchase every share
you've put up for trade.
I'm only telling you this
because I know you can't stop it.
I recommend begging your
friends in California
for more money, maybe they'll
be dumb enough to do it.
And frankly, Dan, I hope they are,
because this has been too fucking easy.
(soft dramatic music)
(cowboy whistling)
(car door closing)
(soft dramatic music)
(upbeat dramatic music)
(doors closing)
(tires squealing)
(birds calling)
- You guys are fucking idiots!
You will rot in prison for this,
for the rest of your fucking lives!
- No, no no, it happens all the time.
Lost souls, they come out
here into the forest and
they can't bear to live another day,
so they decide to end it all.
(birds calling)
It's really toughest
on the kids, you know.
They never understand why.
- Fuck you.
- Don't you look at me, you piece of shit.
You look at him.
He has to understand what he's up against.
That semi that ran into
Mr. Dutton's truck,
was that an accident?
- It was a convenient opportunity.
- Well it ain't so fucking
convenient now, is it?
I want you to tell him about the land.
Tell him how you get it. Go on.
- We inflate the land prices.
Run up the property tax.
Then you price people out.
You know how much the
Yellowstone is worth?
You think I'm gonna be the last person
who's gonna wanna take it?
Your father has two choices.
Either to sell it or to lose it.
That's the fucking truth.
- Now you know, Kayce.
Jimmy, go on and cut him down.
- Fuck you guys!
- Don't you wanna have
your lawyer present?
- This don't feel like a lawyer meeting.
- I saw your son go against Peabody Coal
before the Senate, he is
one hell of a litigator.
- Yeah, he can argue
with he best of them, so?
What is this problem?
- Well, a casino in this valley
will have a negative effect
on our business, your
ranch and the others.
In five years, how many ranches like this
can afford to exist?
- Wanna hear our guess?
Soon as that casino opens,
they'll approach the forest
service for a land lease
and they'll build a ski resort.
- And you know as well as
anyone that ski resorts
are daggers to the heart
in places like this.
- It'll be an ocean of
second homes in 10 years.
- I'm aware.
- I'm sure you are.
Look, my office has no
authority over an Indian casino.
- And yours has no
authority over the land.
And your new AG can't restrict them.
So we need to fight this
outside the lines, Mr. Dutton,
and well, we just don't think they've got
the stomach for that.
- Yeah.
Well, they have the stomach for it.
I don't need partners, fellas.
- Dan Jenkins has a partner, a big one.
- Think of us as allies.
We'd be the perfect allies
for each other, John.
Because there's no part of your business
that benefits ours, and vice versa.
- And when we fight,
it's a zero-sum game.
We'll win at any cost.
- Yeah.
- John?
We just want you to consider it.
- I consider every option, Malcolm,
and I choose the one
that's best for my family.
If it helps you, it's a coincidence.
(soft dramatic music)
- That's not the way you
wear one of those (chuckles).
- You're buying up quite the swath
of land here in the valley.
- You're a long way from
Billings, aren't you, Malcolm?
- I don't consider any part
of this state beyond my reach.
- I'm not sure the state would agree
with you on that, buddy.
- Hm.
Your father is a, he's
not a reasonable man.
I respect that.
I'm not either.
So I wanna be clear about something.
I will not have a casino built
at the gates of Yellowstone.
- We don't want one either.
- But you won't help me stop them.
- I'd go back to Billings, Malcolm.
We'll take it from here.
- Huh.
You see, I just can't, I ...
I can't trust that you will stop them.
Your family has the political
resources to guarantee
this bill never happens, and
yet you won't offer them.
- I think my father's reputation
should warrant a little trust.
- The only thing he
cares about is his ranch,
and when that property tax quadruples,
the only way he'll be able to protect it
is find a new revenue stream.
- That's my job.
- I'm well aware of that.
I'm also aware that the
likeliest source of electricity
for the casino comes from
damming your tributary.
Now your father may not
have thought about that,
but I guarantee you have.
And I am positive that
pretty face has done the math
figuring out how much money you will make
turning the Dutton Ranch into
the Dutton Power Company.
Do you know the story of Susan Rawlings?
- Real estate attorney from Hamilton.
- That's right.
We had a mutually beneficial relationship,
until she figured out
a way to bend the law
to benefit her business
more than my business.
That's the problem with
playing dirty, Beth.
Because when someone plays dirty back,
there's no one to cry to.
There's no charges to file.
There's nowhere to scream
about the injustice you endured
because if you do, all your
filthy laundry just spills
right out in the open,
for everyone to see.
Susan finally realized that.
They moved her.
Somewhere in California where they could
help her move past the trauma.
(soft dramatic music)
It's uncanny how much you look like her.
(keys clicking)
(soft dramatic music)
- Excuse me, can I ...
Hey, no no no.
(Jason groaning)
(dramatic music)
(engine roaring)
(phone ringing)
- [Recording] This is
Beth. Leave me a message.
- Fuck!
Fuck!
(engine roaring)
- This wasn't a crime, Dad.
- This was--
- I know what it is.
(soft dramatic music)
- I'll take care of this.
- [John] Thank you for coming.
Now, you know what they did to me.
- They did something similar to me.
- Yeah?
What they do to you?
- They pulled my liquor license.
They're putting me out of business.
I don't see the logic in it,
attacking all three of us.
- They want you to leave.
They want him to quit building,
and they want me to make him.
To this point, I'd say we
all have played fairly dirty.
But no one's attacked my family on behalf
of your business, and
no one's attacked yours
on behalf of mine.
- Nothing any of us say here
is gonna change our roles.
Our paths will always collide.
We fight.
One of us'll win.
But you've been a good enemy, John.
A fair enemy.
- I don't know if I agree with fair.
But you've kept your fight
with me. I respect that.
- Well, now we face a new enemy.
And they don't play fair.
They'll find the thing you care about most
and they'll kill it.
(soft dramatic music)
- This is like a blood oath,
except we make the cut later.
- I'll call you back later.
(items smashing)
(items crashing)
(glass smashing)
(Malcolm screaming)
(Malcolm breathing hard)
(soft dramatic music)
- You know this gets any
bigger, people are gonna,
gonna start to notice.
(soft dramatic music)
So how far you wanna take this thing, Mal?
- They're not leaving us much choice.
We take this all the way.
- Well this thing doesn't
just stop at John Dutton.
He runs this thing with his children.
- I said!
All the way.
- All right.
So who do you wanna start with?
(soft dramatic music)
- The one he loves the most.
(hooves beating)
(soft dramatic music)
- I'll be covering you on your right.
- Yes, sir.
(soft dramatic music)
- Let's get in place.
You think they got night vision?
- Yeah.
And thermal, you can bet on it.
(soft dramatic music)
- I love you.
- You tell me where my grandson is,
and I'll get you to a hospital.
(Malcolm groaning)
You have my word.
(Malcolm crying)
- Go on, scream.
Scream till whatever makes you wanna
hurt a child to hurt me leaves you.
(soft dramatic music)
If there's a heaven,
and I, I sure hope so,
this is your last chance to do something
that just might get you in it.
(Malcolm inhaling)
You know, I think a lot
about the 10 or so years
I got left before there's
not much left for me to do
but sit around and reminisce.
You on the other hand are
gonna have to cram a lifetime
of reminiscing in the
next 30 minutes or so,
or you can lay there and
not telling me where he is
will be your last thought.
Not whoever you may have loved
or your brother's ninth
birthday, none of that shit.
Your entire lifetime's gonna be reduced
to my grandson's face.
It's up to you, Malcolm.
(Malcolm breathing hard)
- What's he doing?
(Malcolm grunting)
- That's Jupiter up there, the bright one.
Did you know that?
(Malcolm coughing)
- Carter Mees. That's his name.
Whitefish, Mont ...
Whitefish, Montana.
- I'll call for a chopper,
get you to the hospital.
- I ain't gonna make it to a hospital.
- Yeah, well, I gave you my word.
- I won't hold you to it.
- It shouldn't surprise
you they bought it.
Wish we'd bought it.
- It doesn't surprise me they bought it.
It surprises me they knew about it.
I mean, if a company
this big wants to develop
in this valley, we're
the first call, right?
But we weren't, and now
I have New York attorneys
swaggering through our fucking fields.
- Who's Market Equities' main competition?
- MGM, Marriott.
- [Bob] And what does
Marriott own that they don't?
- (sighs) A ski resort?
But we're an hour and a
half from an airport, Bob.
It's too remote for ...
Okay, they're not taking over a resort.
They're building an airport.
But there's no reason to build an airport
because there is no ski resort.
(soft dramatic music)
Who do you know at the
Department of the Interior?
- I know the secretary of the interior.
- Call him. Find out if
they gave them a lease.
They are building an airport
and a ski resort,
and then they're gonna
build a city around it.
- Buy everything you can
around them, Beth. Everything.
- How the fuck did they
know about this place? Huh?
I mean, does Chase manage their funds?
- [Bob] Goldman, I think.
- All right.
Who's the big swinging dick
in hedge funds over there?
- Who runs the hot hedge funds at Goldman?
- [Woman] There's Micah Greenberg's fund
and Roarke Morris, his fund's on fire.
- All right, who's heavy in real estate?
- Roarke, he bridges lines of
credit on resort properties,
then sells them to his fund.
- Fucking shell game.
All right, what's his first name?
- Roarke.
- That's his first name? That's
not a fucking first name.
(soft dramatic music)
You gotta be fucking kidding me.
- You know him?
- It's like Lucille Ball
and Fabio had a kid,
and I have to go make a
Fucking deal with him.
God damnit!
- Continued their downward
trend as two more oil companies
were added to the US trade blacklist.
Both companies are currently being
investigated for securities fraud.
And in the largest dip of the day,
investment firm Market Equities falls
over 7 and a half percent.
- What the fuck?
(soft dramatic music)
(keys clicking)
That fucking bitch.
(soft dramatic music)
- Because she baited them into it.
Every hedge fund manager in
New York is shorting us now.
It doesn't matter if it's true!
The boulder is rolling down the hill
and I can't do anything to stop it.
Look, set a call with shareholders.
We need to start a buyback.
I know.
I fuck ...
(laptop thudding)
I know.
(soft dramatic music)
- Pardon the way I'm dressed.
Just finished my yoga.
- In your robe?
- Do it naked.
Clothing restricts the
body's natural movement.
Be a better world if
we went about our days
just the way God made us.
Have a seat.
So how's it going?
- We been pushing him pretty hard.
- Good, keep pushing.
- I ain't trying to go back to prison.
And I ain't trying to get killed.
- Everything you've done's been justified.
They harassed our livestock,
and you ran them off.
That's the way this'll
play out in a court of law.
Now keep pushing till
he does something else
that we can use in court.
- I wanna bring some more men on.
I don't want a dozen of his wranglers
dragging me through the sagebrush.
- Bring on whoever you like.
But somebody better get
drug through the sagebrush.
Can't sue for damages if
there aren't any damages.
- You don't know John Dutton like I do.
- That's why the job pays so well.
So keep poking him till
that son of a bitch
does something he can't take back.
(soft dramatic music)
- He's sure slow to get the message.
- Maybe we oughta get our boys up here
before we mess with
these assholes anymore.
- It's one fucking guy.
Hell, we're getting paid to stir trouble.
Let's stir some.
(dramatic music)
(wood thudding)
(hoof beats pounding)
(dramatic music)
- Oh shit! We gotta turn back.
- I'm gonna shoot every
one of you sons of bitches!
(dramatic music)
(man groaning)
(man screaming)
(water running)
- Excuse me.
This yours?
- What?
- Found it up here on the bank.
- Not mine, man.
- Not yours, huh?
You sure?
- I said it's not mine.
What the hell are you doing?
- Sure it's not yours, huh?
A little present from the Yellowstone.
(screaming)
(water splashing)
(groaning)
(dramatic music)
(coughing)
(groaning)
Shouldn't be long now.
Good riddance.
(gentle music)